hey everybody caffeine man here and
today I'm gonna be doing a product
review on caffeine gum that's right they
put caffeine and gum and I'm excited to
go over it I'm gonna be going over jolt
meg run and alert gum we'll go over the
caffeine count on each one the flavor
and overall longevity of the gum coming
right up
[Music]
hey everyone thanks for joining me I'm
excited to do this product review today
because I know a lot of people didn't
know there was actually a thing called
caffeine gum so I'm excited to be able
to share something new with you there
are four gums that I want to go over the
first ones called jolt you may know the
name of the company most known for its
soda as well as Meg which stands for
military energy gum so you know who
they're marketing to another brand is
run you can guess or they're marketing
too as well
and lastly alert gum which is made by
five gum and just reminder if you want
to stay informed on all things caffeine
related feel free to hit the subscribe
button and if you like this video hit
the like button as well so let's start
off with Allerton gum the word gum is
made by five gum and five gun is made by
Wrigley's gum doctor might want to
branch out and so far this is the only
one i've been able to find in stores
strangely enough I found it at writing
in Walgreens I saw that one Walmart but
not all the Walmarts carry it yet it
comes in two flavors we have the mint
flavor and you have fruit flavor I've
had the mint one before so today I'm
excited to actually try the fruit one as
well if you can't find a store near you
I'll include a link down below alert gum
has eight pieces in each package each
piece has 40 milligrams of caffeine and
the package sells for about 249 so let's
go ahead and try it out it's easy to
open you pull it out it comes in just
like this each one is individually
packaged and it looks like they have
them grouped in twos in case you want to
have two pieces 480 milligrams I'm going
to start off with one
it's definitely minty and I have a hint
of a bitter taste now in its purest form
caffeine is quite a bitter so sometimes
hard to mask that flavor but the mint is
doing a good job the bitterness is
starting to go away which is good and
now I'm getting a lot of that mint
flavor now I like the flavor I'm curious
how the fruits gonna taste so it has a
much more of a fruit person than a mint
person but I like this so far in doing
research it says that you need to chew
it for 20 minutes in order to get the
full 40 milligrams out of it so not to
bore you I'm gonna continue chewing you
come back and write with maybe 10
minutes my biggest problem with gum in
general is that things like Trident and
big red and some other companies you
start chewing it and no word of a lie
within 5 minutes to 10 minutes it's just
getting hard and loses its flavor and I
just have to spit it out so I'm curious
to see if this can go 10 to 20 minutes
like it's supposed to so it's been 10
minutes and it still has its softness to
it it really hasn't gotten hard at all
and it still has its flavour to it so
I'm pretty certain they will probably go
it's full 20 minutes so next let's try
the fruit here's the package for the
fruit 1 same packaging I'm immediately
hit with the fruit flavor an orange
flavor ooh there's that bitterness again
it's a lot more bitter than the mint gum
I'm probably making a weird face right
now so I'm gonna cut here and then come
back and ten minutes just like with the
other gum and see how it goes and
hopefully that bitterness goes away the
min one went away quicker so we'll see
if this one goes away compete right back
so I'm back and it hasn't been the full
ten minutes yet it's only been six or
seven minutes and the truth is I can't
take it anymore because that bitterness
almost like a chemical flavor now it
hasn't gone away and I still taste a
hint of the fruit but it's not
overcoming that bitterness so I have to
get rid of this forgive me for spitting
out and I need to wash it down with
something and this this get to wash it
down with good good old coconut redbull
you can't go wrong with this stuff I'm
gonna include a link down below because
in every one of my videos I think people
should be drinking this stuff it's the
best thing on the market
as a side note this is not a sponsored
video all of these gums I've chosen
because they're the most common ones on
the market and they have different
amounts of caffeine in them also I'm not
sponsored by Red Bull I just love the
stuff next we're gonna be moving on to
jolt you probably know the name from the
soda company they were started in 1985
well before Red Bull had come to the
states and they marketed it as having
twice the amount of caffeine than most
colas and in truth it was close to three
times the amount a 16 ounce can of Jolt
Cola has 160 milligrams of caffeine in
it which puts it on par with the other
energy drinks of the same size but soda
itself usually has around 50 to 60
milligrams depending on the cola
so it's definitely more than two times
but let her market it the way they
wanted to here we have the jolt come I
haven't found it in too many stores as
of yet I've seen it a Walmart but not
all Walmart's then it said on the
website that they're in stores
throughout the United States this pack
has 10 pieces in it each piece is 40
milligrams of caffeine each and this is
the icy mint flavor so let's try it out
[Applause]
hey I see it minty and it definitely
doesn't have as much bitterness as the
the alert come and tell you the truth I
don't taste much bitterness at all um
I'm gonna get another piece out just to
show you this see if you can get in
there zoom in on that I don't have
anything actually zooming but but anyway
it has little pieces of flecks of blue
in it which I'm guessing is also a sea
mint flavor and as I'm chewing it does
have a little bit of texture to it which
I don't mind because it gives it like
flavor crystals or something like that
but actually pretty good I like this
Joel claims that you don't need to chew
this for 20 minutes you only need to
chew it for five minutes they say it
works four to five times faster than
most of the gums on the market so I'm
gonna go ahead I'm going to chew it for
five to ten minutes and see if it loses
its flavor because even though they say
it takes five minutes to get all the
caffeine out of it I still like to be
able to chew a gum for like ten minutes
so it's been ten minutes and the only
downside to the gum is that it's a bit
small smaller than the Wrigley's so when
you chew it you're not gonna be blowing
any bubbles or anything well it didn't
get hard but it's still chewable and I'd
recommend having two pieces if you want
to be able to more easily chew it
surprisingly there's actually no taurine
in the gum like most energy products
have they say that an official study in
2008 that it showed no proof that
taurine increased or decreased energy so
they stick with guarana and ginseng
which have both been shown to increase
energy if you can't find jolt in a store
near you I'll include a link down below
next we have a run gum you can guess who
they're advertising for this one they
promote their brand to help maximize
your performance and to give you more
energy during workouts and I use the
quotes because that's what they say on
their websites but they also say it
helps you run in general and keeps you
running through the day so it's sort of
a play on words for the word run similar
to when Duncan says America runs
Duncan one also claims to help you stay
focused at work so will they cover in
all their bases each piece of run gum
has 50 milligrams of caffeine in it
slightly higher than the other brand so
far and it can be found at Target it is
slightly more expensive though a pack of
two pieces is a dollar ninety-nine if
you buy a 12-pack is twenty one dollars
so it comes out to a dollar seventy-five
but still quite high compared to the
other brands out there so let's see if
it's worth the price I'm gonna stick
with one piece for now it's immediately
harder than the other ones it kind of
broke apart into a few pieces when I
started to bite it not to say it's
crunchy but it doesn't have that soft
white hmm it's got a cool mint flavor I
taste a hint of bitterness but still not
as bad as Wrigley's not to say that the
release was bad but yeah I had that
immediate flavor of bitterness and the
other two gums haven't seemed to have it
so far the mint flavor is slightly
different than the others I'm not sure
how to describe it it reminds me of that
bengay smell but it doesn't taste like
bengay now the eat bengay but I think
you know what I mean I need to look up
what the hopefully or bengay is so let
me get back to you in a few minutes to
see how this one goes
all right I'm back listen it's only been
five minutes I'm getting rid of this
it's already starting to go hard if
there's one thing I don't like it's when
gum goes hard too fast maybe it's just a
pet peeve of mine but when you have
chewing gum
you're supposed to be chewing on it not
getting a workout for your mouth Plus
given the price I won't be buying that
anytime soon and like I said the flavor
wasn't that bad if you like bengay still
given all the other factors I'm not a
fan and I'm gonna need to rinse out with
something
coconut berry Red Bull it's really good
next we're moving on to the Meg gum I
gotta say I'm excited to try this one
out they have a great story online and
how do you recommend you checking out
their website to read up more on them
I'll include a link down below to their
website so you can check out for
yourself and for right now I'm actually
gonna read we're
forward a couple of paragraphs from
their website because I can't do it
justice I'm gonna read it right from my
computer
it's a hold on I'm gonna be looking down
I usually like to look at the screen but
I'm looking down to read this military
energy gum and the US military have
worked together since 1998 to help stop
fatigue related injuries and deaths meg
was developed to help soldiers stay
alert with a rapid release and easy to
carry caffeine supplement clinical
studies have proven increased physical
and cognitive performance as well as
improved marksmanship and overall
vigilance under sleep-deprived
conditions how can you not want to buy
it after reading a description like that
it seems like they put their time in and
they've done the work are you still not
convinced well do you like caffeine I
think you do otherwise you wouldn't be
here well unlike the other gums which
have a measly 40 milligrams of caffeine
each piece of Meg caffeine gum has 100
milligrams of caffeine in it that's
right 100 milligrams in one piece now
don't you want to try it it makes me
want to try it I'm gonna try some right
now
each pack has five pieces in it all with
100 milligrams each
and you can get a 24 pack for $26 that's
just slightly over $1 pack which makes
this the biggest bang for your buck
let's see how it tastes it's a nice blue
color
I like the flavor this is the mini
flavor which is Arctic mint it's big
similar to the Wrigley incise cigar I
density to it plus lots of chew I don't
get any bitterness from it I'm really
liking it I think I've got a new
favorite gum well I'll let you know in
ten minutes I'll be right back alright
I'm back it's been ten minutes and it's
still going well it's still got its got
like a hint of crunch to it I think it
may be from the aeroshell but it's still
very soft still very flavorful still
very good I'm a big fan of this and it
says that it takes between five and
fifteen minutes for you to get its full
caffeine out of it I'm not sure what
else to say I'm just enjoying this too
much I should probably spit it out for
the rest of the video though so there
you have it
I went over four brands of caffeine gum
I think the best one is Meg is the best
price it's the most amount of caffeine
and it's the best flavored one I highly
recommend it if you can't find in stores
click the link below it'll take it to
Amazon where you can purchase it through
an affiliate link or just go to military
energy gum as well and you can purchase
it from them stay tuned next week I'm
excited to announce that I'm doing a
video of a holiday gift giving guide for
the caffeine lover that's right you'll
be able to find gifts for your loved
ones who love coffee tea and other
caffeine related products or maybe even
just something for yourself it's gonna
be a great video and I hope you can find
something for that special caffeine
lover in your life once again thanks for
joining me if you like this video feel
free to give it a like and if you want
to stay informed on all things caffeine
related hit the subscribe button good
stuff
you